thefederalistpapers.org 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is critically important to us. The Federalist Papers Project adheres to a few fundamental principles:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * In our blogging products, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals: If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data please contact our [support team.](https://thefederalistpapers.org/contact)

The Federalist Papers Project  (“ **The Federalist Papers Project** ”) operates **[thefederalistpapers.org](https://thefederalistpapers.org/)**. It is The Federalist Papers Project’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, The Federalist Papers Project collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. The Federalist Papers Project’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how The Federalist Papers Project’s visitors use its website. From time to time, The Federalist Papers Project may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

The Federalist Papers Project also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on WordPress.com blogs. The Federalist Papers Project only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to The Federalist Papers Project’s websites choose to interact with The Federalist Papers Project in ways that require The Federalist Papers Project to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that The Federalist Papers Project gathers depends on the nature of the interaction

In each case, The Federalist Papers Project collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with The Federalist Papers Project. The Federalist Papers Project does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

The Federalist Papers Project discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on The Federalist Papers Project’s behalf or to provide services available at The Federalist Papers Project’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using The Federalist Papers Project’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. The Federalist Papers Project will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, The Federalist Papers Project discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when The Federalist Papers Project believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of The Federalist Papers Project, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an The Federalist Papers Project website and have supplied your email address, The Federalist Papers Project may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with The Federalist Papers Project and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. The Federalist Papers Project takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. The Federalist Papers Project uses cookies to help The Federalist Papers Project identify and track visitors, their usage of The Federalist Papers Project website, and their website access preferences. The Federalist Papers Project visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using The Federalist Papers Project’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of The Federalist Papers Project’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If The Federalist Papers Project, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that The Federalist Papers Project goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of The Federalist Papers Project may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by The Federalist Papers Project and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Many of our advertising partners are part of the Network Advertising Initiative. You may opt-out of behavioral advertising for Network Advertising Initiative member companies by following the link below and opting-out of all or some of the advertising networks: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, The Federalist Papers Project may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in The Federalist Papers Project’s sole discretion. The Federalist Papers Project encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy.
